MISSION 52 "IT'S JUST A THOUGHT."
（任务52 心中的想法）
Who can answer this question?
那我要请同学回答这个问题
Komi.
古见同学…
Actually, Ushiroda.
跳过 请牛路田同学回答
Yes, sir. The Treaty of Portsmouth.
是 朴茨茅斯条约
Yes, that's right.
很好 答对了
-Hey, uh. It's not bullying, you know? -Open page 125.
-不 老师不是在耍着你玩 -接下来翻到125页
-It's more like the opposite. -It'll be on the test so take note.
-是恰恰相反才对 -这里会出考题 大家要仔细听
-BREAK TIME -Sports Day.
-（下课时间） -运动会
And the culture festival.
还有文化祭
It's all so nostalgic.
全都让人怀念
I don't want to study.
我不想读书
Those are your true feelings.
这才是你的真心话吧
It's almost winter break, right?
就快放寒假了吧？
Yes, it is. I can't wait!
没错 真令人期待！
Komi, where do you want to go?
古见同学 你想去哪里玩？
"Are you reading my mind?"
“在对我使用读心术吗？
"I know you are. Heh heh."
我能看出来喔 呵呵”
That's what that face says.
这样的想法全写在她脸上
Let's go, Komi.
我们走吧 古见同学
What's up, Nakanaka?
你怎么了？中中同学
Tadano! You are supposedly good at reading minds.
只野同学 你似乎很擅长读取人心！
But it looks like you failed to read mine!
但我不是人类 看来你这招对我没用！
Um, you're trying to trick me by assuming I can read minds
什么？你以有人懂得读心术为前提
and thinking, "You're reading my mind," right?
测试我是不是 在读取你心中的想法吗？
How did you know?
你怎么知道？
SUDDENLY FEELS EMBARRASSED.
（突然感到丢脸）
Tadano understands what it's like to have an overactive imagination.
只野同学很了解中二病的心情
I see.
原来如此
You want to know what Komi is thinking?
你想知道古见同学心中的想法？
Yes.
是啊
As Komi's sworn ally,
身为古见同学的盟友
I must learn to understand Komi's feelings.
我必须理解她心中的想法
And as someone who can read her mind,
所以常常读懂古见同学想法的人
Tada… you…
就是只…你这家伙…
I thought I'd ask for help.
我想要拜托你帮忙
You can call me whatever you like.
你想怎么称呼我都可以
Let me think.
我想想
Even I don't know exactly…
话虽这么说 其实我也只是隐约理解她…
Your methods. Teach them to me too.
把你的方法也传授给我吧
She's here.
不知为何她过来了
Alright. Let's observe some scenarios
那我们来猜猜看在各种情况下
and try to guess what Komi is thinking.
古见同学心中有什么想法吧
That's a good idea! How unlike you.
什么？好像有点有趣呢 不像是你会想出来的点子
Unlike?
“不像”？
Clean up the balls!
把球收好！
Hey, that's alright.
等等 不用麻烦你啦
I'll do it for you!
我来就好！
Got it!
捡到了！
Yeaaaahhhh!
太好了！
Now, what is Komi thinking?
那么大家猜猜看 古见同学现在心中的想法吧
Are you kidding? That's too easy!
你在小看我吗？ 只野同学 这太简单了！
"I'm free of a boring task. Where's Yamai?"
“不用处理麻烦事了 山井在哪里呢？”
-Right? -Wrong!
-对吧？ -答错了
Where did you get that cue card?
那张纸板是哪里来的？
Here I am! Komi!
我在这里喔 古见同学！
"Very good, peasant."
“辛苦了 领民们”
Wrong. You have a cue card too.
答错了 原来你也有纸板啊
-The answer is, "I want to tidy up too!" -FEELS GUILTY
-正确答案是“我也想要帮忙收拾” -（感到很不好意思）
Are you sure?
你确定这是正确答案吗？
Probably.
大概是对的
Komi, can I borrow your electronic dictionary?
古见同学 借我电子辞典
10 MINUTES LATER
（十分钟过后）
And then…
然后啊…
Okay, now try it with this situation.
接下来各位猜猜看 在那状况下她现在心中的想法吧
"Shut up and give back my dictionary."
“别聊天了 快把电子辞典还我”
-Right? -Wrong.
-对吧？ -答错了
But I agree with you.
虽然我也有同感
"They're talking, so it's hard to approach them." Totally.
大概是“他在跟别人聊天 没办法去攀谈”吧
That's part of it.
她确实有一点这种想法
-Very close. -What?
-但还差一点点 -什么？
The answer is, "Are they gossiping about me?"
答案是“他们在聊我的八卦吗？”
Wow! A rainbow! There's a huge rainbow!
天啊 是彩虹 有好大的彩虹喔！
Let's see! Where is it?
什么？我也要看！
Wow, it's huge!
超大的彩虹！
This is an easy one. Give it a try.
这一题很简单 猜猜看吧
"I'll do what Yamai does,
“我要跟山井一样
and take a picture of the rainbow for social media.
拍下彩虹的照片 分享在社交媒体
Oh, I should tell Yamai my account!"
对了 我必须把账号告诉山井！”
-Yeah! -Nope.
-对吧？ -答错了
Are you doing this on purpose?
你是故意答错吗？
Heh.
可恶
"Who cares about social media? Don't post pictures of the sky, dirtbags."
“不要在社交媒体 分享无聊的天空照 你们这些杂草”
That's just your personal opinion!
那是你个人的意见吧！
Wrong.
答错了
-Huh? What do you mean? -DIRTBAGS?
-中中同学 你这话是什么意思？ -（杂草？）
The War of the Women is breaking out again.
女人的战争一触即发
She doesn't fuss!
她没有大惊小怪！
Even if a huge rainbow appears, Komi doesn't fuss!
古见大人就算天上出现巨大彩虹 她也不会大惊小怪！
Komi's a much bigger person than that rainbow!
她的心胸比那个大彩虹还宽大！
Wrong.
答错了
KOMI WANTS TO GO SEE IT BUT CAN'T JOIN THE GROUP.
（虽然想要看彩虹 但无法融入大家的古见同学）
-HOME ECONOMICS -Work with your group to make the dish.
-（家政课） -每个小组都要分工合作
Komi, you wash the vegetables.
那么古见同学 你负责洗菜吧
-Huh? Komi? -Okay, how about this…
-怪了 古见同学？ -那大家猜猜看她那样是在想什么吧
Hey!
喂！
"I'm thinking about the next step in the recipe." This is it!
我的答案是“她在思考 料理的下一个步骤”
"I don't know the next step in the recipe." It's gotta be this.
不 她是在想 “料理的下个步骤是什么？”
Huh? Komi's good at cooking, you know.
笑死人了 古见同学厨艺很好
Huh? Whatever!
什么？谁知道啊
The answer is, "Thinking about the rainbow."
正确答案是“她还在想刚刚的彩虹”
-DIDN'T GET TO SEE IT. -She was still stuck on that!
-（结果刚才没看到彩虹） -她还在念念不忘啊！
"I want to eat Yamai's home cooking!"
“我想吃山井亲手做的料理！”
"I want to invite Nakanaka to eat!"
“我想约中中同学吃饭！”
"I want to be with Yamai!"
“我想见山井！”
"I wonder where Nakanaka is?"
“中中同学在哪里？”
"I love Yamai!"
“我喜欢山井！”
"I want to play games with…"
“我想跟中中同学再玩一次游…”
I'm the one who knows Komi best.
我比较了解古见同学
I've hung out with Komi alone you know.
我跟古见同学曾经单独一起玩过
Neither of you have gotten one right yet.
你们两个从头到尾没对过一题
K-Komi!
古见同学！
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
（你们在做什么？）
What? What indeed.
你问我们在做什么？你说呢？
We just happened to be walking together.
我们只是碰巧走在一起罢了
-Don't misunderstand. -Yeah!
-别误会了 -没错！
"I noticed that you were watching me."
“我从途中就发现你们在看我”
"You were having fun talking, too."
“你们好像聊得很开心”
It's over.
完蛋了
-She's angry! -She's totally angry!
-她生气了！ -她绝对生气了！
We didn't mean anything bad…
我们其实并没有…
by it.
恶意
WANTS TO JOIN IN.
（也想跟大家一起玩）
Since we're all here.
大家难得聚在一起
Let's go to a cafe after school.
我们放学后去喝杯茶吧
Why?
为什么？
-NOD -Is it really okay?
-（点头） -她答应了？
At the very least let me pay for yours!
那至少让我帮你出钱吧！
No, I'll pay! Let me pay!
不 让我请客吧 我来付钱！
-Me! -No, me!
-我要请客！ -我要付钱！
NOBODY HAS TO PAY FOR ME. JUST STOP FIGHTING.
（大家不用帮我出钱 别吵架了）
Okay.
好的
KOMI! ME! KOMI! ME!
（我对古见同学更… 我对古见同学更…）
MISSION 53 "IT'S JUST A FANTASY, PART 2."
（任务53 妄想2）
Several days after, "Of all the girls, who would you date?"
讨论“想跟班上 哪个女生交往？”后过了几天
The boys got together again.
他们又聚集在一起
The second round of "Of all the girls, who would you date?"
“想跟班上哪个女生交往？” 第二次讨论会
Shall we begin?
开始吧
They're back at it?
他们又要讨论啊？
We failed to reach a conclusion last time.
结果我们上次没有做出结论
Everyone thought about it at home, and we put something together.
所以我们各自回家思考后 大家一起反复推敲
We've finally made a Komi episode!
我们终于想出古见同学的故事了！
Let's watch, along with two more episodes!
请和其他两个完成的故事一起看！
Part of me is looking forward to this!
我竟然感到有点兴奋！
OF ALL THE GIRLS, WHO WOULD YOU DATE? ONEMINE VERSION
（想跟班上哪个女生交往？ 尾根峰同学篇）
I'm so glad the weather is nice.
太好了 风和日丽
Yeah!
就是说啊
Ta-da! I made a picnic lunch!
你看！我做了便当
Not a word! I love how she does that silently!
安静无声！我喜欢在那一刻 保持沉默的尾根峰同学！
She has immense big sister vibes.
散发出无法估量的姐姐风格！
Onemine is the picture of stability.
尾根峰同学感觉好有安定感
OF ALL THE GIRLS, WHO WOULD YOU DATE? OTORI VERSION
（想跟班上哪个女生交往？ 尾鸡同学篇）
I'm home.
我回来了
Welcome back!
欢迎回家！
Do you want dinner?
你要吃晚饭了吗？
What's wrong?
你怎么了？
I made a terrible mistake at work.
我今天在工作时犯了无法挽回的错误
I'm done for.
我可能完蛋了
There, there.
好乖
It's alright.
不用担心
You'll be okay.
你不会有事的
-Whoa. -I'm gonna cry.
-糟糕 -我快哭了
I wish she was my mom!
真希望她是我妈妈
Those guys must be so tired.
看来他们很疲累
OF ALL THE GIRLS, WHO WOULD YOU DATE? KOMI VERSION
（想跟班上哪个女生交往？ 古见同学篇）
The era has changed!
时代变了！
Anyway, that's going to happen to overthrow the shogunate.
也就是说 因为那样才能推翻幕府
My liege.
正是如此
I see.
这样啊
And when that happens,
所以才会那样啊
Japan will have a bright future.
日本的未来充满光明的希望
Yes.
是的
What an empty conversation…
好模棱两可的对话
This is an investigation!
我们奉命来搜查！
Who goes there?!
来者何人？
Save your breath!
无需多言！
A windmill!
风车！
My husband is not going to meet his end here.
外子可不能死在这里
Escape while you can.
劝你们快逃
O-Osho!
阿硝！
I'll be the one to face you.
由我来对付你们
I'll take several heads
你们几个人的首级
before you go.
就留在此处吧
A period drama was the only way I could imagine being with Komi.
我只能想象在时代剧中 和古见同学交往的场景
You did what you could.
辛苦你了
Alright, so who do you want to date?
那么大家想要跟谁交往？
I'd like someone who's like a buddy.
我想找相处模式像朋友的人
But I also want a video game partner.
但我也想找愿意陪我打游戏的人
But it's gotta be…
不过果然还是…
Ko…
古…
Meeting adjourned!
解散！
Fantasies must be done in secret (from girls).
所谓的“妄想” 不能让任何女生知道
BOY'S FANTASY EPISODE RANKING NUMBER 1: NAKANAKA!
（男生妄想故事排行榜 第一名 中中同学！）
NOT THAT I CARE! (CARES A LITTLE)
（我才不开心呢！ 有一点开心）
Deep, dark, glimmering hair.
乌黑茂密、亮丽且有光泽的发丝
Clear skin without a single blemish.
完美无瑕 具透明感的肌肤
At once both like a regal empress and a mother goddess.
有霸气又慈祥
An absolutely incomparable presence.
散发出无与伦比的存在感
Komi.
古见同学
Even she…
就连这样的她…
-GURGLE -PUNCH!
-（肚子叫） -（捶打）
…sometimes sleeps in and misses breakfast.
有时也会因为睡过头 来不及吃早餐
LUNCH BREAK
（午休时间）
My name is Makoto Katai.
我是片居诚
My hobby is sewing patchwork.
兴趣是拼布
The other day, I made my first friend.
我上次首度交到朋友
And I met Commu, a mentor for communication, which I find difficult.
也有一位善交际同学当了我师父 在我不擅长的人际沟通方面会指点我
My high school life is going smoothly!
我的高中生活一帆风顺
Today I'm going to invite Tadano to lunch.
我今天想邀请只野同学与我共进午餐
Watch me, Mentor.
看看我的表现吧 师父
-LEER -SHIVER
（微笑 一阵寒意）
Here I go.
很好 去搭话吧
I've thought of the perfect line for inviting him to lunch.
我已经想好约他吃午餐的台词了
-That was nice of the literature teacher… -Tadano, hey.
-语文老师今天好温柔… -只野…
Oh no! Was that too casual? I'm acting friendly!
糟糕！我直呼他的姓氏了 仿佛我们感情很好！
But maybe a little too familiar?
这样算装熟吗？
Hello.
同学
What's up, Katai?
什么事？片居同学
I forgot my line!
我把台词忘光了！
Commu is watching me.
善交际同学看着我
-She really is scary. -STARE
-她真的好吓人喔 -（盯着看）
Are you alright?
你没事吧？
I think he wants to eat lunch together.
他想跟我一起吃午餐吗？
Was I going to ask him to eat outside?
我本来打算约他在室外吃吗？
No, it's cold outside.
不对 外面太冷了
But in class with everyone watching… What if he's annoyed?
可是教室里众目睽睽… 他说不定根本不想跟我吃饭
Anyway I have to find the words. Uh…
总之我必须开口约他才行 我想想看…
Let's take a walk.
给我过来
EVERYONE'S FEELINGS INCLUDING KATAI.
（每个人的感受 包括片居同学）
Now I've done it.
我搞砸了
That was so rude of me.
真是太失礼了
I wish there was a hole I could crawl into.
如果有洞 我真想钻进去
Sorry, I'm gonna go today.
抱歉 我今天就 不一起吃饭了 我出去一下
YOU'RE GOING?!
（你要过去吗？）
Why does this always happen?
为什么老是发生这种事？
-Hey! -Huh?
-喂！ -什么？
Hey, Katai!
喂 片居同学！
A miracle?
这是奇迹吗？
LUNCH
（吃午餐）
Wow! Lunch with a friend.
太棒了 我竟然能跟朋友共进午餐
It's a dream come true!
我的梦想终于成真了！
I'm sure my mentor must have said something.
一定是师父刚才帮我说话
-Go to him! -Mentor!
-你去找他吧！ -师父！
Thank you my ment…
谢谢你 师…
-Mentor! Why did you come? -WORRIED ABOUT TADANO.
-师父！你怎么跟过来了？ -（担心只野同学所以跑来看）
Eating lunch together isn't the goal.
我的目标不该只是一起吃午餐
Having fun together and getting closer as friends is the goal!
我必须炒热气氛 和他拉近距离 这才是我该设立的目标
She's watching over me.
所以你会在那边守望我啊 师父
I can do it!
我会办到的！
Let's eat!
我要开动了
Did your mom make it for you?
这是你妈妈做的吗？
-Got any hobbies? -Is this speed dating?
-你的兴趣是什么？ -我们在相亲吗？
Um, I read comics and I play video games a little.
我想想 我喜欢看漫画和打游戏
Oh.
是喔
A-Alright!
很好！
That conversation went great, didn't…
刚刚的对话很顺利吧？师…
-She looks disappointed! -CAN'T UNDERSTAND WHAT SHE IS SEEING.
-她看起来很不满！ -（无法理解在眼前发生的状况）
I've got to show how friendly we're getting.
我必须跟只野同学表现得更要好
Oh! I know!
对了 还有那招！
Open up!
来 嘴巴张开
Even Tadano couldn't help but flinch.
对这举动连只野同学 都忍不住感到退缩
HE WAS DISTURBED BUT HE STILL ATE IT.
（虽然吓一跳 还是乖乖张嘴的只野同学）
Yay!
太好了！
How about it! Tadano and I are getting…
怎么样？师父 我跟只野同学很要好…
-No? Mentor, you're so strict! -KOMI HAS COMPLICATED FEELINGS.
-还是不够吗？师父真严格！ -（古见同学莫名感到心情复杂）
What more can I do?
我还能做些什么？
Ah, yes.
原来如此
My mentor is signaling what to do.
师父已经暗示我了
G-Got it.
我知道了
I'm a little embarrassed, but I'll try it!
虽然有点难为情 但我试看看吧
GRAB
（紧贴）
A Working Club Hostess Tells All
《现役酒店小姐传授
51 Ways to Get Friendly, Chapter 1, page 12.
与人拉近距离的51种方法》 第1章 第12页
"Physical touch is best!"
“总之先肢体接触”
-This is what my mentor was trying to say. -RIGHT AROUND HERE
-师父 原来你想告诉我这一点 -（这里）
I-I'm shy, but if it'll bring us closer.
虽然有点害羞 但如果这么做能让我们变要好…
Pulling away?
他感到很讨厌？
W-What should I…
我到底该怎么做？
BUT HE CAN'T BREAK AWAY.
（但没放开）
-KOMI VISION -You ate my lunch.
-（古见同学的视角） -你刚刚吃了我的便当吧？
-SHAKEDOWN -Pay me 20,000 yen.
-（勒索） -付两万日元给我
-She looks like she's going to come over! -WANTS TO STOP HIM BUT IS SCARED.
-天啊！师父好像想要冲过来！ -（想阻止但怕到不敢过去！）
I can't do this anymore! Help me, Mentor!
我受不了了 快救救我 师父！
Chaos.
很混乱
You don't have to force it.
你不需要勉强自己
I'm not entirely sure what you were trying to do.
虽然对于你做出的一些举动 我看不出你是想做什么
But when you're with me, you don't have to act tough.
但你跟我在一起时不需要逞强
You can just be yourself, and that's fine with me.
只要展现平时的自己就行了 这样我也会很开心
Okay.
好
-GURGLE -TUMMY NOISES.
（咕噜 肚子叫的声音）
Huh? Komi?
怪了 古见同学？
Would you like to eat with us as well?
你要不要跟我们一起吃午餐？
I'll introduce you to Katai.
我介绍片居同学给你认识
Lunch with my mentor?
跟师父一起吃午餐？
Katai, this is Komi.
片居同学 她是古见同学
I think you two would get along.
你们应该很合得来
Both of you…
你们都…
You can't say that!
那件事不可以说出口！
Najimi!
驯染！
Since when…
你是从什么时候…
Pretty much since the beginning.
我很早就待在这里了 只野同学
I'll say it again. You can't say that!
我再告诉你一次 那件事不可以说出口！
After all, it's funnier this way!
因为这样比较有趣嘛！
Anyway, let me join you for lunch.
我也要跟你们一起吃午餐
Sure.
好啊
Everyone ate lunch together.
大家一起吃了午饭
MISSION 55 "IT'S JUST ROASTED SWEET POTATOES"
（任务55 烤地瓜）
Roasted sweet potatoes!
来买烤地瓜喔！
Hot and delicious!
热腾腾又美味！
-FIDGET -Sweet potatoes!
-（坐立不安） -烤地瓜！
Roasted sweet potatoes!
来买烤地瓜喔！
FLOATING
（模糊冒出来）
GHOST
（幽灵）
KOMI'S AFRAID TO CALL OUT
（不知道该怎么开口的古见同学）
ROASTED SWEET POTATOES
（烤地瓜）
KOMI CAN'T HELP BUT SHAKE HER HEAD.
（忍不住摇头的古见同学）
KOMI DOESN'T KNOW WHY SHE SHOOK HER HEAD.
（不知道自己为什么 要摇头的古见同学）
ROASTED SWEET POTATOES 300 YEN
（烤地瓜 300日元）
REAL LIFE "RED LIGHT, GREEN LIGHT"
（处在玩“一二三木头人”状态）
COLD
（冷飕飕）
ONE…
（一…）
TWO…
（二…）
FIVE!
（五！）
-KOMI DID PAY FULL PRICE. -THANK YOU!
（乖乖付钱的古见同学 谢谢惠顾！）
MAYBE FIVE WAS TOO MANY.
（五个好像太多了）
WARM
（热腾腾）
Ever since the culture festival, something has been bothering me.
举办文化祭后 有件事让我耿耿于怀
Everyone in the school saw me dressed as a girl!
全校同学都看到我穿女装了！
TADANO
（只野同学）
Why did I dress up like a girl?
我为什么要穿女装啊？
I could have at least changed for the after-party!
我至少该在后夜祭换掉衣服啊！
A new page was added to Tadano's dark history.
只野同学的黑历史写下了新的一页
I got all caught up in the moment and acted like a fool!
因情绪太激昂 而不禁做出蠢事的学生就是我！
EXACTLY.
（正是如此）
How can I deal with these feelings?
我该怎么宣泄这样的心情？
Komi's face at that moment.
古见同学当时的表情
Are we…
这是…
What was I trying to say then?
我当时本来打算说什么？
No! No, no, no!
不！
I don't know what you're doing, but stop shaking the bed!
我不知道你在做什么 但你不要摇晃床铺啦
I've got to think calmly.
冷静地思考一下
I would never feel that way.
我不可能会产生那种想法
Komi's beautiful and cute, too.
古见同学确实漂亮又可爱
But that's precisely why…
所以与我根本…
No, no, no. What am I thinking?
不对 我到底在想什么啊？
I'm going out.
我出去一下
-To buy porn? -No!
-你要去买色色的书吗？ -才不是！
What odd timing.
她现在怎么会在外面？
G-Good evening, Komi. What a coincidence.
晚安 古见同学 好巧喔
BLUSH
（脸红）
You bought some roasted sweet potatoes?
你去买烤地瓜吗？
It's so dark out, I'll walk you home.
天色这么暗 我送你回家吧
Are you alright?
你没事吧？
I should invite her out.
试着约她出去玩吧
I don't have anything happening during winter break.
反正寒假时闲闲没事做
I do like hanging out with Komi.
跟古见同学相处很开心
As a friend, as a friend! Of course.
我当然是以朋友的身份约她出去啦！
But if I'm going to ask her to hang out,
不过既然要约她出去玩
I should suggest a specific day and activity.
必须先决定出去玩的日期 还有具体要做什么
Okay, take care, then.
那你要小心喔
I failed.
失败了！
For me?
你要给我吗？
Thank you.
谢谢你
Let's do something together over winter break too!
我们在寒假也一起玩吧
Thanks for this.
谢谢你的地瓜
See ya.
再见
Winter break has begun.
寒假要开始了
BONUS SCENE
（片尾彩蛋）
That was delicious!
我吃饱了！
Oh yeah, Komi!
对了 古见同学！
You should get Katai to write his name!
你让片居同学签那个吧！
-Ta-da! Komi's Book of Friends! -JUST A MEMO PAD
-请看 《古见友人账》！ -（只是普通的记事本）
We're getting all of Komi's friends to write their names!
我们会请跟古见同学 变要好的人在这里签名！
I see. My mentor wants the names of her apprentices.
原来如此 师父的弟子 要在这里签名啊
TADANO, NAJIMI, AGARI, YAMAI YADANO, NAKANAKA…
（只野、驯染、上理 山井、矢田野）
So many apprentices!
师父有好多弟子！
My mentor is so formidable!
师父好可怕！
Katai became her apprentice.
片居同学成为了她的弟子
Subtitle translation by: Claire Tanaka
字幕翻译：吴敬美